import 'question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Who is the current president of the United States?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Joe Biden',
      'b) Donald Trump',
      'c) Barack Obama',
      'd) George W. Bush'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. Who won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2021?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Albert Einstein',
      'b) Syukuro Manabe and Klaus Hasselmann',
      'c) Marie Curie',
      'd) Richard Feynman'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. In which continent is India located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Europe',
      'b) Asia',
      'c) North America',
      'd) South America',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. Who is the author of the novel "To Kill a Mockingbird"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) J.K. Rowling',
      'b) Harper Lee',
      'c) George Orwell',
      'd) Jane Austen'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which city is known as the "City of Love"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Paris',
      'b) Rome',
      'c) Barcelona',
      'd) Venice',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. Who is the first woman to win a Nobel Prize?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Marie Curie',
      'b) Mother Teresa',
      'c) Amelia Earhart',
      'd) Rosalind Franklin'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. Which planet is known as the "Red Planet"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: ['a) Earth', 'b) Jupiter', 'c) Mars', 'd) Venus'],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the capital of Japan?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Beijing',
      'b) Tokyo',
      'c) Seoul',
      'd) Bangkok',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. What is the currency of Brazil?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: ['a) Brazilian Real', 'b) Peso', 'c) Euro', 'd) Dollar'],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '10. Who is the director of the movie "The Shawshank Redemption"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Steven Spielberg',
      'b) Christopher Nolan',
      'c) Quentin Tarantino',
      'd) Frank Darabont'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '11. In which year did the Titanic sink?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: ['a) 1905', 'b) 1915', 'c) 1912', 'd) 1920'],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '12. What is the capital of Australia?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: ['a) Sydney', 'b) Canberra', 'c) Melbourne', 'd) Brisbane'],
  ),
];
